Shubham Gulati

Senior Software Engineer • Certified Cloud Architect • 7 Years Experience • B.Tech & M.Tech Waterloo, ON • linkedin.com/in/iamshqulati • shubhamqulati.com

SUMMARY

Shubham is an award-winning Senior Software Engineer with 7 years of exceptional IT experience at industry leading U.S. and Canadian professional services firms. He has a Masters degree in Computer Science & Engineering and is certified in AWS. His core competencies include cloud-native web application development using Java, Spring Boot, and Microservices.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Technology Consultant, Deloitte Consulting

India - 2022-2022

- ◆ Led a backend team to enhance the client's usage reporting application, resulting in a 25% improvement in user satisfaction.
- Promoted software engineering best practices, leading to 35% increase in reliability and adherence to high quality standards.
- Conducted in-depth technical training sessions for new hires in the team, improving the team's onboarding efficiency by 20%.
- Actively participated in sprint planning with key stakeholders, ensuring timely reporting and successful delivery of the project.

Technology Consultant, Deloitte Consulting

India – 2019-2022

- * Architected and developed user personalizations for a client's Customer Support Portal, increasing user satisfaction by 20%.
- Developed a reusable foundation for all microservices, enhancing the system reliability and reducing technical debt by 30%.
- ◆ Integrated a Spring Cloud Config Server and HashiCorp Vault for easy management of secrets, reducing security risk by 40%.
- Resolved performance bottlenecks, improving the performance and scalability of critical features like search and downloads.

Technology Analyst, Deloitte Consulting

ndia - 2018-2019

- Transformed complex HR Portal monolith with 750+ APIs to cloud-native microservices, improving system scalability by 35%.
- Developed efficient microservices using Spring Boot, Java, Apache libraries, resulting in scalable and maintainable backend.
- Delivered high precision modules like Mergers & Acquisitions and Career Advancement, enhancing system reliability by 20%.
- Delivered well-organized API collections and OpenAPI endpoints to QA and Support teams, reducing transition time by 50%.

Associate Software Engineer, CGI Inc

ndia - 2016-2018

- ◆ Developed innovative framework to manage state of production system using JMX, reducing maintenance downtime by 95%.
- Migrated applications from Oracle WebLogic Server to Spring Boot, reducing operation costs and improving maintainability.
- Delivered a comprehensive set of unit tests for services using JUnit and Power Mockito, decreasing production bugs by 10%.

EDUCATION

Postgraduate Certificate, Computer Application Security, Conestoga College
Postgraduate Certificate, Cloud Computing & Blockchain, Saskatchewan Polytechnic
Master of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Jaypee Institute of Information Technology
Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Jaypee Institute of Information Technology

Waterloo, ON

Saskatoon, SK

India

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Developer Associate, Amazon Web Services (AWS)
AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate, Amazon Web Services (AWS)
AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Pursuing FPDELC1KXFF1QXK5 JJMV6422RJ1Q1NWV

SKILLS

Backend	– Java, Microservices, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring Web, Spring Security, SQL, ORM, JPA, Hibernate, REST
	– Git, JUnit, Power Mockito, Normalization, OpenAPI, Swagger, GraphQL, Jetbrains IDEA, SDLC, Agile, Scrum
Infra / Cloud	– AWS (EC2, S3, DynamoDB, CloudFormation, IAM), GCP, DevOps, GitHub Actions, Docker, Jenkins, SonarQube
Security	– pfSense, GVM, Nessus, Cryptography, PKI, Risk Assessment, Threat Modelling, Ghidra, IDA, Reconnaissance
Frontend	- SSG, SSR, Typescript, React, HTML, CSS, TailwindCSS, Next.js, Astro.js, Jetbrains Webstorm, Linters, Formatters

HONOURS & AWARDS

Conestoga	 High Distinction Award, Outstanding academic achievement in Computer Application Security. 	2024
Conestoga	 Best of Program Award, Best Capstone Project in Computer Application Security program. 	2024
Saskpoly	- Dean's List Award, Outstanding academic achievement in Cloud Computing & Blockchain.	2023
Deloitte	 Applause Award, Technical contribution to the success of the eCX project. 	2022
Deloitte	 Outstanding Award, Technical contribution to the success of the STAR Migration project. 	2020
Deloitte	 Outstanding Award, Technical contribution to the success of the HRAlly project. 	2019
Deloitte	 Applause Award, Project delivery excellence during the development of the HRAlly project. 	2019
Deloitte	 Spot Award, Critical support during CSP 2.0 project go-live. 	2019
Deloitte	 Applause Award, Delivery excellence during CSP 2.0 project development. 	2018
CGI	 Apex Award, Unsupervised delivery, and individual contribution to the M2M GDSP project. 	2017

PROJECTS

n.
eline.
chain.
nstall.
teraction.

PUBLICATIONS

Research Paper

- An efficient technique to control road traffic using Fuzzy Neural Network System.
- ◆ Published in the IEEE Journal https://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ICRITO.2014.7014723